BU Records: Delta Sigma Pi, Inclusive: 1930-1994, undated, Bulk: 1940-1958
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Delta Sigma Pi
Inclusive: 1930-1994, undated, Bulk: 1940-1958
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/339
Delta Sigma Pi: Beta Iota chapter
2 document boxes and 1 oversized box
The collection includes administrative records, membership lists, minutes, photographs, booklets, and newspaper clippings pertaining to the Beta Iota chapter of Delta Sigma Pi at Baylor University. Dates range from 1930 to 1994, with the bulk of the collection dating from 1940-1958.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Delta Sigma Pi was founded at New York University in 1907 by Alexander Frank Makay, Alfred Moysello, Henry Albert Tienken, and Harold Valentine Jacobs. These four students set to graduate in 1909, sought to create a business fraternity that valued scholarship, social activity, and affiliation between the world of commerce and its members. At the time there were only a handful of business schools in the United States and The School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance was one. In 1908 the name Delta Sigma Pi was adopted, and the by-laws were approved, with the Fraternity’s badge and colors approved quickly thereafter. In 1975 Delta Sigma Pi became the first business fraternity to initiate women. Today nearly 300 universities and colleges in the United States, Canada, and Mexico are part of the Delta Sigma Pi network. The Beta Iota Chapter of Delta Sigma Pi at Baylor University began on December 9th, 1930 with nineteen initiates, both majors of business and graduates of the institution. Currently Baylor University’s premier professional business fraternity, this chapter aims to develop professional business leaders and create strong relationships with the Hankamer School of Business at Baylor University.
Scope and Content
This collection begins in 1930 and ends in 1994, with some items undated. The bulk of the collection is membership lists and membership forms. The Administrative Records series is the largest within the collection and includes directory for members, by-laws, pledge manuals, membership lists, membership forms and photographs. This series contains records that were redacted for personal identifying information and other privacy concerns. Contact archivist for details. The Minutes series includes chapter minutes and proceedings of grand chapter congresses. The Publicity/Press series includes formal event information, the Beta Iota ledger, banner, advertisements and newspaper clippings. The Correspondence series is the smallest group of the collection and includes invitations to various events held by the organization as well as correspondence to events.
Some materials in the collection were compiled by previous Texas Collection staff members over time and kept in subject files. These materials were added to the collection during processing.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, this collection was arranged by document type and in labeled folders. Most of the folder titles were retained. Currently, the collection is arranged in four series: I. Administrative Records, II. Minutes, III. Publicity/Press, and IV. Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/339.
Related Resources
Related references
“Another Frat.” Baylor Lariat, November 20, 1930. Accessed 2019 October 14.
“Fraternity History,” Delta Sigma Pi. Accessed 2019 October 14.
“Our Chapter,” Delta Sigma Pi. Accessed 2019 October 14.
“Values and Purpose,” Delta Sigma Pi. Accessed 2019 October 14.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Records and correspondence.; Baylor University -- Societies, etc.; Baylor University -- Students -- Correspondence.; Baylor University -- Students.; Baylor University. Beta Iota — records and correspondence.; Delta Sigma Pi. Beta Iota Chapter (Baylor University) -- Records and correspondence.; Delta Sigma Pi.
Subjects
Administrative records.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence; Delta Sigma Pi. Beta Iota Chapter (Baylor University) -- History.; Greek letter societies -- Texas -- Waco.; Minutes (Records); Photographs.; Promotional materials.; Registers (Lists)
- Administrative Records, 1930-1958, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series is the largest series within the collection and contains administrative records of Beta Iota, including by-laws, pledge manuals, membership information and information related to good standing and job placement. This series is in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print
  - By-Laws, 1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pledge Manuals, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership Forms, 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership Forms, 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Forms, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Membership Forms, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership Forms, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership Forms, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Membership Forms, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Membership Forms, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Membership Forms, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Membership Lists, 1938-1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Membership Lists, 1938-1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Membership List Card Catalog, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Directory and Job Placement, 1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - National Directory of Graduating Seniors of the Class of 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Directory of Graduates Available for Employment During 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Directory of Graduates Available for Employment During 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Delta Sigma Pi Presents Its Graduates for the Year 1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Delta Sigma Pi Presents Its Graduates for the Year 1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Delta Sigma Pi Presents Its Graduates for the Year 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Membership GPA List [RESTRICTED], undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of Good Standing, 1940-43, 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Memorandums, 1930-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1947-1958; 2
  This series contains Beta Iota chapter minutes and proceedings from Grand Chapter Congresses. This series is in good condition.
  - Chapter Minutes, 1947-1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chapter Minutes, 1947-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Proceedings of the 16th Grand Chapter Congress August 27. 28 & 29, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Proceedings of the 17th Grand Chapter Congress September 7, 8 & 9, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Proceedings of the 18th Grand Chapter Congress September 9-12, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Publicity/Press, 1947-1958, undated; 3
  This series contains Beta Iota formal events, advertisements, banners and newspaper clippings. This series is in good condition.
  - Formal Events, 1933-1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Homecoming Breakfast, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Homecoming Parade, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Rose of Delta Sig, 1946-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Annual Banquet, 1935-1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Southwestern Provincial Convention, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Advertisement, 1950-1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Beta Iota Banner, 140-1947, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Ledger, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1941-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, 1954, undated; 4
  This series contains invitations and replies to Beta Iota events. This series is in good condition.
  - Correspondence, 1940-1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Banquet Reply Postcards, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)